Osvald Laudrisen

Senior FullStack Engineer

Dublin, Ireland • osvaldlaudrisen@gmail.com • github.com/osvald-laudrisen

SUMMARY

I am a highly versatile full-stack software engineer. I have helped numerous companies take an idea and turn it into a product that serves thousands to millions of users. I've built the software that powers SignaPay's service centers for scheduling from scratch and worked at major tech companies, such as Automate Technology, MedoSync, and VIA Software. Known for building fast and exceptionally well, I can work on either end of the stack, integrate CI/CD, perform end-to-end testing, and more.

HARD SKILLS

Backend: Express.js, Laravel, Ruby, Go, Solidity

Frontend: Svelte, React.js, Next.js, Redux, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Vuex

Preferred Libraries: Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Chakra UI, Element UI

Database: GraphQL, MySQL, MSSQL, Redis, MongoDB, Firebase

Cloud: Cloudinary, Google Cloud, AWS, Git, Bitbucket

Tools: Wasp, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes

Others: Ember.js, Pusher, Sequelize, Prisma, Ethers.js

SOFT SKILLS

Communication: Verbal and Written communication, Presentation, Active listening, Constructive Feedback

Time Management: Stress management, Prioritizing, Organization

Problem-solving: Analysis, Logical reasoning, Observation, Decision making **Teamwork:** Conflict management and resolution, Collaboration, Idea exchange

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

2023.12 - Now

Self-employed

- Contributed to open-source projects and Wasp community.
- Joined team projects for building customer-facing web applications and MVPs (React / SCSS / Express / GraphQL), increased monthly users to 2M on average
- Designed and deployed the application-level components using React, TailwindCSS and Storybook.
- Continuously improved UI/UX design level and created optimized, reusable components with Makerkit.

Senior Software Engineer

2022.7 - 2023.11

VIA Software, United States

- Built a microservice backend application using Go and PostgreSQL, leveraged its concurrency features and lightweight footprint to build scalable and efficient distributed systems.
- Integrated and managed smart contracts on Ethereum blockchain using **Solidity**, **Truffle**, and **Web3.js**, enabling secure and seamless digital asset transactions and attracting a growing user base.
- Led cross-functional teams in planning, development, and execution of platform features, fostering a collaborative and agile environment and improving overall team productivity by 20%.
- Implemented continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD) pipelines, optimizing the development process and ensuring high-quality, timely releases with a 15% reduction in deployment time.

• Developed an **innovative cryptocurrency strategy model**, increasing platform liquidity and attracting new investors, leading to a 30% increase in token valuation.

Lead FullStack Engineer

2020.10 - 2022.7

SignaPay, United States

- Oversaw the front-end development of a **DeFi platform**, streamlining access to decentralized financial services and applications, resulting in a **30% increase in user adoption**.
- Developed responsive, high-performance user interfaces with Vue, Nuxt.js, and Ant Design, optimizing for accessibility and cross-device compatibility, achieving a 25% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Implemented best practices for web performance, security, and usability, resulting in a 50% faster and more secure platform experience.
- **Mentored** junior front-end developers, fostering their professional growth and enhancing team collaboration, leading to a 15% increase in overall team productivity.
- Introduced progressive web app (PWA) features, enabling **offline functionality** and improving **mobile user experience**, contributing to a 30% increase in mobile user retention.

Senior Web Developer

2018.9 - 2020.9

Websense, Ireland

- Played a key role in building and maintaining a high-performance web application using **React**, **Redux**, and **GraphQL**, resulting in a 40% improvement in application performance and user satisfaction.
- Integrated Stripe, Plaid, Tink and Truelayer to implement OpenBanking and transparent Payment in several projects.
- Participated in an **AI content generating project** with Flask and React.js.
- Optimized application performance by implementing **code-splitting**, **lazy-loading**, and **server-side rendering** techniques, leading to a 30% reduction in load times.
- Participated in SMS & MMS application development using Twilio, and developed a firmer understanding
 of VoIP service.

Intermediate FullStack Developer

2017.2 - 2018.8

Self-employed, Remote

- Implemented internationalization(i18n) features for several web applications to support **multiple** languages, expanding the application's global reach and increasing user base by 20%.
- Attended fullstack development courses to obtain more understanding about the Progressive Web Applications.
- Contributed to the development of a cutting-edge real estate platform, seamlessly integrating React.js
 for an intuitive user interface, Laravel for robust backend functionality, and MSSQL for efficient data
 management, demonstrating proficiency in modern web technologies and delivering a high-performance,
 scalable solution that streamlined property listings and transactions.
- Collaborated with UX/UI designers to translate designs into intuitive and functional interfaces, maintaining consistent branding and user experience, and achieving a 20% increase in user engagement.

FullStack Developer Internship

2016.5 - 2016.12

MedoSync, Ireland

- Enhanced developer experience, converting large portions of the platform incrementally to TypeScript.
- Created a web app MVP for a store delivery management platform to create, manage, and monitor deliveries using Laravel, React and Redux.

Web Developer Internship

2015.5 - 2016.4

Automate Technology, Ireland

- Developed user-friendly website, including **optimized check-out page** that increased user clicks, and subsequently customer purchased by 20% using React.
- Initiated self-motivation to acquire development skills, enhancing personal marketability and expertise.
- Cultivated strong ties to the technology community through a demonstrated ability to deliver quality work.

EDUCATION

University College Dublin, Dublin

Bachelor of Science — Computer Science

2012 - 2015

PROJECTS

Trackd Music - Award-Winning Social Music App https://trackdmusic.com

• Vue.js, Next.js, Typescript, Laravel, Firebase

Cropper Finance - Automated market maker https://cropper.finance

• Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Typescript, Web3, Ant Design, RESTful API, Solana, Defi

Bitpool

https://play.bitpool.gg

• React.js, Node.js, Typescript, Web3, MUI, RESTful API

Joepegs - Trusted NFT Marketplace on Avalanche https://joepegs.com

• Next.js, Typescript, Chakra UI, Web3, AWS, Avalanche, Smart Contract, Solidity

NFTOnPulse - NFT Marketplace https://nftonpulse.io

Node.js, React.js, Typescript, Material UI, Web3, Smart Contract, Solidity, Ethers.js

Janus Network - Private blockchain https://janusnetwork.jo

• Next.js, Typescript, Avalanche, Material UI, Defi, Smart Contract